studentfinancewales.co.uk 2018-03-24

# Privacy policy - Student Finance Wales

  * Home >

Student Loans Company Limited is registered as a Data Controller with the Information Commissioner under the Data Protection Act 1998 and is committed to respecting your online privacy. We will apply appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information you share with us. The level of protection will be based on an assessment of the harm that is likely to be caused by the loss or unauthorised disclosure of the personal information you give us. The information you provide will be processed by SLC in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. This Privacy Policy covers all websites operated by Student Loans Company but does not extend to links to other external websites within this site.

We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of the information you submit to us. All personal information you provide is transferred via a secured connection. This is completed under 128 bit SSL (Secure Socket layer) encryption, which is a leading security standard for the transmission of data within the e-services industry.

We may monitor usage of our website to enable us to update and tailor same to the needs of our users. We may also keep a record of those links which are most regularly used, thus enabling us to provide the most helpful information to our users.   As part of the operation of our service, some of our web pages may use cookies (and other tracking technologies).   A ‘cookie’ is a small text file downloaded on your computer’s hard drive.  A cookie's main objective is to identify users and personalise their visit by customising web pages for them; for example, by welcoming them by name next time they visit the same site. This enables us to collect information such as the time spent on our website and the pages used. The cookies on this website are only valid whilst you are using our service and expire when you log out and close your browser window.

We do not conduct any long-term tracking of your visits to our site with cookies and you can always delete your cookies when you are deleting your temporary internet files. However, you should note that this will affect all sites that have provided cookies, not just ours. Further information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at [www.aboutcookies.org.](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "Link to 'about cookies website' \(opens in a new window\)") It should be noted that our website will not work without cookies.

We will process, use and disclose information that we collect from you, or that you provide to us, in the following ways:

  * __to help provide services to you.
  * __to administer your participation in the Student Loans Scheme.
  * __where authorised by you, to arrange for the collection of repayments made by you in relation to your Student Loans Account.
  * __to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * __to provide you with information on services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you.
  * __to carry out our obligations and exercise our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * __to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * __to notify you about changes to our service.
  * __to monitor the performance of the website.

You agree that SLC can use your personal data for such purposes, unless and until you inform SLC otherwise. SLC will not supply, transmit, sell or otherwise provide your personal data to any third party without your consent under any circumstances, except where required or permitted by law.

We have a legal obligation under the Data Protection Act to ensure that all information held and processed about you complies with the principles of the Act. To achieve this aim we need accurate information about you. Should you discover that SLC is holding personal data relating to you which is inaccurate, please notify SLC as soon as possible. SLC will then correct its records, and notify third parties to whom such personal data may have been supplied in accordance with this policy.

Under the terms of the Act you have the right to obtain a copy of the information we hold about you, upon payment of the appropriate fee. If you wish to obtain a copy, please write to:

Customer Assistance team  
100 Bothwell Street  
Glasgow  
G2 7JD

You will need to enclose a cheque or postal order for £10 and mark your letter ‘Subject Access Request’.

This Privacy Policy is not intended to – nor does it - create any contractual or other legal rights. It is, however, a guide to our online protection standards.
